https://youtu.be/MUW6H5F-GT4 Okay, here's what I want you to do...
Tôi muốn bạn thực hiện điều này.
Imagine that you're sitting in front of an auditorium, and you're asked to perform
Hãy tưởng tượng bạn đang ngồi trước một thính phòng, và bạn được yêu cầu trình diễn
for a roomful of people by tapping out of tune for everyone to hear. The tune should
trước căn phòng đông nghịt người bằng cách vỗ nhịp. Đó nên là giai điệu
be something that you think everyone would know.
mà bạn nghĩ rằng ai cũng biết.
A few examples that most people would know from North America, Australia, or the UK might
Một vài ví dụ mà những người ở Bắc Mỹ, Úc, hay Anh có thể biết đến như
be ‘Twinkle, Twinkle, Little Star’,
"Twinkle, Twinkle, Little Star"
‘Baa, Baa, Black Sheep’,
‘Baa, Baa, Black Sheep’,
or ‘Raindrops Keep Fallin' on My Head’.
hay 'Raindrops Keep Fallin' on My Head’.
Now imagine that you're standing in Matt's position and that there's a hundred people
Giờ thì tưởng tượng bạn đang đứng ở vị trí của Matt và có hàng ngàn người
watching you perform in front of this auditorium. I want you to estimate how many of the 100
đang dõi theo bạn biểu diễn trước thính phòng này. Tôi muốn bạn ước đoán xem có bao nhiêu trong số 100 người nghe
listeners would be able to name the tune that you're tapping.
có thể đoán được tên của giai điệu bạn đang vỗ.
Okay? So go to the next section and enter a number between 0 and 100.
Được chứ? Hãy đến mục tiếp theo và nhấn một con số giữa 0 và 100.